(僧たち)うわっ!!
うわっ！
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
夢… か…。
何だったんだ？ あれは…。
A dream, huh...?
What was that...all about...?
Hidden Leaf Library
Nightmare
(サイ)「他人に いち早く
自分を理解してもらうには➡
In order to have others quickly
understand you...
まず 他人との心の距離を
近づけることである。
first you must get closer
to their spirits.
例えば 相手の呼び方➡
For example, when calling people
by their names,
「さん」や 「君」などをつけて
呼んでいては➡
it is impersonal to call people
using "san" or "kun."
他人行儀で いつまでたっても
距離は縮まらない。
You will never get closer
to them like that.
まずは思い切って
相手の名前を呼び捨てにしたり➡
You might first try taking the plunge
and call people by
their first name only...
あだ名や愛称などを決めて
呼んでみては どうだろう？
or try using a nickname or
term of endearment.
そうすれば 特別な存在として➡
If you do that, others will feel much
more familiar about you...
ずっと身近に
感じてもらえることが…」。
as a special person...
なるほど。
I get it...
あった あった！
Oh, found it.
ん？
《サクラ : あれ？ サイじゃない》
What...? Isn't that Sai?
イチャイチャパラダイスとは…。
Make-Out Paradise is...
(サクラ)画集でも探しにきたの？
ん？
Did you come looking for a book
of paintings or something?
サクラさん。
Sakura...
へぇ～ 本とかも読むんだ。
So, you read books, huh...?
まぁ 少しはね…。
Well...a little bit.
ん？
《フッ！ サイも結構
人間くさいとこあんのね》
So even Sai has quite
a human side to him, huh...?
(サクラ)これから 私とナルトとで➡
Naruto and I were just on our way
カカシ先生のお見舞いに行くんだけど
サイも一緒に行かない？
to visit Kakashi Sensei
in the hospital...
Why don't you come with us?
カカシ先生…。
Kakashi...Sensei...
アンタも 同じカカシ班だし➡
You're on Team Kakashi too,
so you should meet him...
顔合わせしといたほうがいいしね。
((オレにとっては 復讐がすべてだ。
Revenge is everything to me.
復讐さえ叶えば➡
If I can carry out my revenge,
オレがどうなろうが
この世がどうなろうが➡
it's no concern of mine what
happens to me, or to this world.
(知ったことじゃない))
((だが 大蛇丸に
オレの体を差し出すことで➡
But if I can obtain the power
to accomplish that
それを成し得る力を
手にできるなら➡
by giving my body to Orochimaru,
(こんな命 いくらでもくれてやる))
then I'll give him as much of
this life of mine as he wants.
((今なら見える。
I can see it now...
これが お前の未知の力だったか。
So this is your unknown power, huh...?
(まさか お前の中に
こんなものがいたとはな))
Who would've thought...
you'd have something like
this inside of you...
なんで あの夢が？
Why did I have that dream...?
(サクラ)ナルト！
ん？
Naruto!
あ？
なんだってばよ。 サイも一緒かよ。
What? Sai's with you, too?
うん 図書室で偶然 会ったから。
I bumped into him at the library.
な～んだ。
せっかくサクラちゃんと２人きりで➡
Oh...and here I was working out
my plan to walk with you,
デートっぽく歩くプラン練ってたのによ。
just the two of us,
like we were on a date!
(サクラ)
ったく そんなヒマがあったら➡
If you've got the time to be
doing that,
忍術の勉強でも
してるっていうの！
you should be studying up
on Ninjutsu or something!
ん～ 勉強ねぇ…。
Study, huh...?
２人とも よく あんな
かた苦しいとこ行けるってばよ。
How can you guys even go to
a stuffy place like that?
ナルトこそ
体ばっかりじゃなくって➡
You should train your mind a little
and not just your body.
頭のほうも
少しは鍛えたほうがいいわよ。
(サクラ)アンタ ホント バカなんだからさ。
You're really an idiot, after all.
《やっぱり サクラさんも
ナルト君のことを呼び捨てに…》
I knew it... Sakura is calling
Naruto only by his first name...
ん～ サクラちゃん
それは言い過ぎだってばよ。
That's harsh, Sakura.
ナ ナルト… サ サクラ。
N-Naruto, S-Sakura...
(２人)ん？
ボクも会話にまぜてもらって
いいかな？
Could you guys include me
in the conversation, too?
あぁ… いや 本で読んだんだ。
Oh! Well, I read in a book...
他人と
すぐに打ち解ける方法とか。
about how to open up to
other people right away...
(サイ)それで 本には
名前を呼び捨てにしたり➡
And in the book, it said to call people
by their first names only
あだ名や愛称で呼べと。
and to use nicknames and
terms of endearment...
そうすれば 親近感がでて
すぐに仲よくなるって。
It said if I did that there would
be a sense of friendliness
and we'd be able
to get along right away.
へぇ～ なんだ。 お前も
そんなこと気にするんだな。
Oh, so you're concerned
about stuff like that, huh?
それで さっき 図書室で…。
So that's what you were doing
in the library...
うん。
Yeah.
(サイ)で ２人のあだ名とか愛称とか
考えたんだけど➡
And...I was thinking about nicknames
and terms of endearment
for you guys...
うまく思いつかなくて…。
But I couldn't really come up
with anything good...
とりあえず 呼び捨てで。
So I'll just call you guys by
just your first names for now...
《サイが そんなに真剣に➡
I can't believe Sai would think
so seriously about us...
私たちとのこと
考えてたなんて…》
そんなのはさ 考えなくても➡
You don't need to think about stuff
like that.
自然に
決まっていくもんだってばよ！
It just happens naturally!
愛称とか あだ名なんて➡
For nicknames or terms
of endearment,
その人の特徴とか
言えばいいのよ。
you should just say that
person's character trait.
例えば… ほら ナルトなら➡
For example,
if you're talking about Naruto...
バカナルト！ とか
アホナルト！ とかね！
Idiot Naruto! Or moron Naruto!
Or something.
って サクラちゃん…。
それは 飛びすぎだってばよ…。
Sakura, you're taking things
too far with that.
《なるほど… 特徴を！》
I get it...A person's character trait...
《あの サイがね…。
I can't believe this is Sai...
初めて会ったときとは
すごい違い！》
He's totally different from
when I first met him...
あ… そんなに見つめられても…。
Huh...?
You don't have to stare
at me like that...
あ！
ありがとう コツがわかったよ。
Thank you. I've got
the hang of it now...
ブス。
Ugly.
しゃ～んなろ～!!
それは ぶっとびすぎだってばよ！
Sai, you're really taking things
too far with that!
え？ 何がです？
うが！
Huh? What do you mean?
(サクラ)コラァ！
(サイ)うぐっ！
Sakura, why'd you have to
hit me, too...?
サクラちゃん… なんで オレまで…。
そうか…
キミが 新しいチームのメンバーの…。
I see... You're the new team member.
Sai, was it? Nice to meet you.
サイだっけ？ よろしくね。
はい…。
Right.
ちょい サクラ こっち こっち。
Sakura, come here for a second.
あの２人 ケガしてるけど
ケンカでもしたの？
Those two are hurt...
Did they fight or something?
ケンカっぱやい ナルトのことだから
想像は つくけど…。
It'd be no stretch of the imagination
with someone hot-tempered like Naruto...
えっ いえ 別に 何も！
N-No, nothing happened at all...
We're all getting along fine!
みんな 仲いいですよ！
(カカシ)あ そうなの。
それなら いいんだけどね。
Oh, I see...Then I guess it's okay.
アハハ アハハ…。
《この人が… 根でも噂された
あの… はたけ カカシ…》
This is Kakashi Hatake,
the one rumored about
in the Anbu Black Ops Training Division.
ナルト。
うん。
Naruto...
Yeah...
カカシ先生 オレたち 今回の任務で…。
Kakashi Sensei...
About our previous mission...
I heard about everything
from Yamato.
ヤマトから 全部 聞いたよ。
サスケのこともな。
About Sasuke, too...
We don't have time...
もう… 時間がねえんだってばよ。
このままじゃ…
もう少しで アイツが…。
At this rate, he'll soon be...
でも… 今の力じゃ
サスケを連れ戻すことが できねえ。
But I can't bring Sasuke back
with the power I have now...
アイツ 強くなりすぎてる！
He's gotten too powerful...
まぁ だったら それ以上に
強くなればいいだけだろ。
Well then, you just have to get
more powerful, right?
あ…。
でも…。
But...the speed of Sasuke's development
was extraordinary even in my eyes.
私の目から見ても
サスケ君の成長スピードは➡
尋常じゃなかったんです！
綱手様に聞いたら
修業に 禁術や➡
When I asked Lady Tsunade,
she said there's a possibility
they're using Forbidden Jutsu
薬物投与を用いてる
可能性もあるって。
and perhaps drugs in his training...
あっちには あのカブトもいるから➡
And they've got Kabuto with them, so...
人体実験をしてるような
ヤツらの考えは➡
There's probably no way to find out,
in a book like this,
こんな本じゃ
調べようもないだろうけど…。
how people who conduct
experiments on humans think...
(カカシ)だったら こっちも
それ以上に➡
Then we just have to
rapidly get more powerful.
急激に 強くなるしか
ないでしょうよ。
でも… どうやって!?
But how do we do that?
オレが ただ何も考えずに
寝てるだけだと思った？
Did you think I was just lying here
not thinking about anything?
I thought about that the whole time.
ずっと考えてたんだよ。
で 思いついた。
And...I figured it out.
…ただし この方法は
ナルトに向いている。
However, this approach is
suited for Naruto...
Or...rather I should say it's an approach
only Naruto can do.
と いうより ナルトにしか
できない やり方だけどね。
その修業で ナルト
お前は ある意味では➡
In that training...
in a sense you might
just exceed me, Naruto.
オレを超えるかもしれないな。
オレが… カカシ先生を超える？
I'll...exceed you, Kakashi Sensei?
そうだ。
That's right.
この修業では
オレが つきっきりになる。
I'll be with you the whole time
on this training.
で 今までとは
かなり違った修業になる。
And it will be a different type of training...
ど… どんなこと
するんだってばよ。
Wh-What're we going to do...?
お前だけの最強の忍術を作る。
We're going to create a Ninjutsu
of ultimate strength just for you.
つまり 螺旋丸を超える
新しい忍術を身につけてもらう。
In other words,
you're going to learn a new Ninjutsu
that will exceed the Rasengan.
ただし それなりの力を
手に入れるには➡
However, the acquisition
of such a power
それなりに見合った
膨大な時間と努力がいる。
will require an enormous amount
of time and effort.
小説の主人公みたく 数日で
ポンポン 強くなれるわけもない。
You can't get strong instantly
after just a few days
like the hero in a novel.
それに 螺旋丸のように
すでに できあがっている術を➡
And it's completely different from
being carefully taught
and learning a Jutsu
丁寧に教えてもらいながら
会得するのとも わけが違う。
like the Rasengan that
has already been created.
膨大な時間って…
だから さっきも言ったけど➡
An enormous amount of time...
But I just said we don't have time!
Sasuke will be...
もう 時間がねえんだよ！
サスケは もう…！
だから それを短時間でする方法を
思いついたのさ。
What I'm saying is, I figured out a way
to do it in a short amount of time.
どうやって？
それはな…。
How do we do it...?
Well...
(アスマ)体調は どうだ？ カカシ。
How're you doing, Kakashi?
(いの)アスマ先生！
ノックぐらい しなさいってば！
Asuma Sensei, you could
at least knock!
(チョウジ)こんにちは。
Hello.
(シカマル)なんだ…
ナルトとサクラじゃねえか。
Why it's Naruto and Sakura...
任務はもう… ん？
Is your mission already...
お前は あんときの…！
You're that guy from back then...
あ！
だ… 誰？
Wh-Who is he...?
《どうして 今日は
いきなり こんな…。
Why is all of this happening
so suddenly today...?
落ち着いて… まずは 笑顔で…》
Relax. First, smile...
どうも。
Hello.
(綱手)報告 ご苦労だったな。
Thanks...for the report.
(暗部)では 私は これにて。
I'll be going now.
暁の行動が いよいよ
本格化してきましたね。
The Akatsuki activity is finally
getting into full swing.
ヤツらがまた 木ノ葉周辺を
にぎわすようになるのも➡
It's only a matter of time
before they start churning things
up around the Leaf.
時間の問題ですね。
たしかに 大きな危機ではあるが
それは ヤツらを叩くチャンスでもある。
Indeed, this is a significant crisis.
But that's also our chance
to attack them.
(綱手)いよいよ
ちんたらしてられないな。
We can't just sit around anymore.
Hidden Leaf Hospital
(チョウジ)な～んだ
そういうことだったんだ。
Oh, so that's what was going on.
納得 納得。
I buy that.
サイっていいます。
どうか 呼び捨てにしてください。
My name's Sai.
Please just call me by my first name.
へぇ… なんか 結構
かっこいいじゃない。
Hey, he's pretty cute...
He kind of resembles Sasuke, too.
少し サスケ君似だし～。
見た目はね。
On the outside.
But he's quite different on the inside.
中身は だいぶ違うから。
空気読めないし。
He can't really read the mood
of a room, you see.
サスケのことは 綱手様から聞いた。
I heard about Sasuke from
Lady Tsunade.
今度は オレも何かあったら
協力するぜ。
I'll help you guys out in the future
should something happen.
めんどくせえ 中忍試験も
終わったしな。
I'm finished with those troublesome
Chunin Exams, after all.
お前また 中忍になりそびれたな。
You missed out on becoming
a Chunin again, huh?
あぁ。
Yeah...
まぁ
それどころじゃなかったか…。
Well, I guess that was the least
of your problems, huh...?
何しに来たんだよ？
ゾロゾロ 連れてきて…。
What're you doing here
with the whole gang in town?
ここは 休憩室じゃないぞ。
そうだな。
This isn't a break room, you know.
That's right...
お前ら 先に 焼肉Ｑへ
行っといてくれ。
You guys go on ahead to "Barbe-Q."
よかったら カカシ班のみんなも
一緒に行くといい。
You guys from Team Kakashi
should go too if you want.
(チョウジ)イェイ！ 焼肉～！
(いの)賛成！
Yay! Barbeque!
I second that!
ウフフフ！
I'll sit next to Sai!
《サイ君の隣に座る！》
オレは カカシと２人で
ちょっと 話がある。
I need to talk to Kakashi alone
about a few things.
焼肉は オレのおごりでいいからな。
The barbeque is on me, okay?
って… ちょい待ち！
あのさ あのさ！
Hey, just a minute!
Listen! Listen!
さっきの話… 修業の話の続きは
どうなるんだってばよ！
What about the rest of the discussion
about my training?!
そうだな う～ん…
ま またあとでな。
That's right...Hmm...
Well, we'll get to that later.
あとで～!?
すげ～ 気になるってばよ！
Later?! I'm really curious about it!
ま オレが入院している間は
修業は始められないんだ。
Well, we can't start training while
I'm still in the hospital.
そう あせるな。
Don't be so impatient.
遅いってば サクラちゃん。
あれ？ シカマルは？
What took you so long, Sakura?
What? Where's Shikamaru?
親父さんと 薬用の角を
とりにいかないとならないから➡
He said he was going home
because he has to get some horns
for medicinal use with his father.
帰るってさ。
(いの)ふ～ん。
No kidding?
いつも 任務の打ち上げには
必ず 出てたのにね。
He always shows up
for end-of-mission parties...
珍しいわね。
This is a first for him...
《忠告 聞いてない》
She isn't taking my advice...
(チョウジ)よ～し！ シカマルの分も
食べるぞ～！
All right! I'll eat Shikamaru's share!
って チョウジ！ 食べる前に サイ君に
私たちの自己紹介しないとさ。
Hey, Choji!
We have to introduce ourselves
to Sai before we eat.
あ… あぁ… そうだね。
Oh, oh...right.
どうやら 国の外が
騒がしくなってきたようだ。
It appears things have started
getting turbulent outside the land...
やはり…。
I knew it...
ヤツらの目的が 尾獣である以上➡
As long as their objective
is the Tailed Beasts,
この里を… いや ナルトを
狙ってくるのは 目に見えている。
it's a foregone conclusion that
they'll target this village,
I mean, Naruto.
オレを外すことはないでしょ。
オレだって 暁の動向は気にかかる。
There's no need to leave me out, right?
I'm also concerned about
Akatsuki developments.
ナルトは 大丈夫なんですか？
Will Naruto...be okay?
暁のヤツらが襲ってきたら
あの 我愛羅でさえ…。
If those guys from the Akatsuki attack...
Even Gaara couldn't...
ま ダメだろうね。
Well, he probably won't be okay.
今は…。
Right now anyway.
ハハハ…。
フフン…。
どうも。
Hi...
《サイ : 早く打ち解けるには
初めが肝心だからな。
First meetings are very important
in order to quickly open up to people...
あだ名や 愛称を
すぐに決めなきゃ》
I have to decide on nicknames
and terms of endearment right away...
えっと ボクは
秋道一族の 秋道 チョウジ。
Uh, I'm Choji Akimichi
of the Akimichi Clan.
よろしく。 えっと サイだっけ？
Nice to meet you.
Uh, you're Sai, right?
よろしく。 えっと…。
Nice to meet you...uh...
《特徴 特徴！》
Character trait...character trait...
《あっ まさか!?》
《えっ もしかして あの禁句を》
Don't tell me...
He's not going to say
that taboo word, is he?!
デ…。
Fa...
サイ… チョウジの前じゃ
デブってのは 絶対 禁句だ！
Sai! "Fatty" is absolutely a taboo word
in front of Choji. Got it?!
わかったな！
今 何か言いかけた？
(サクラ)ハハ… 別に なにも。
Did he...
start to say something just now?
No, it's nothing...
あっ そう。
I see.
《サイ : あだ名ってのは 難しいな》
It sure is tough coming up
with nicknames...
私は 山中花店の娘で
山中 いのって言います。
My name's Ino Yamanaka.
My family owns
the Yamanaka Flower Shop.
よろしくぅ！
Nice to meet you.
《サイ : 女の人の場合は
特徴を そのまま言えば➡
In the case of a girl,
saying a character trait
just makes them angry...
怒らせることになる…。
つまり その逆を言えば
そうはならないってことだから》
In other words, if I say the opposite...
《サクラ : やめなさい サイ…》
Don't do it, Sai...
《いけぇ！ サイ！
思いきりぶちかましちゃって！》
Go, Sai!
Let her have it good!
よろしく！ えっと… えっと…。
Nice to meet you...uh...
pretty lady.
(サイ)美人さん。
フゥ～… はっ！
(サクラ)なんで
いのんときは そうなんのよ！
Why do you say that
when it's Ino?!
(サクラ)シャー!! んなろ！
あぁ やめろってばよ サクラちゃん！
Stop it, Sakura!
(サイ)ゴフッ！
(２人)子 巳 申 卯 卯
酉 丑 丑 申。
Rat, Snake, Monkey, Rabbit, Rabbit,
Rooster, Ox, Ox, Monkey, Rat...
Ram, Dragon, Boar, Boar, Horse
Rabbit, Rabbit, Dragon, Tiger, Rabbit...
Rooster, Boar, Snake, Dragon, Rat
Rat, Boar, Dragon, Snake, Monkey...
Snake, Rooster, Ox, Snake, Snake
Horse, Horse, Ram, Rooster, Dog...
Dog, Dragon, Rat, Rat, Tiger, Rooster
Dragon, Rabbit, Monkey, Monkey...
Ox, Snake, Rabbit, Dragon...
(フドウ)チッ！
(フドウ)違ったか…。
Wrong one, huh...?
おい チョウジ！
この肉は オレのだからな！
ふんっ！ 早い者勝ちだもんね！
だから キミは デ…。
うんっ!?
わぁ～っ サイ！ それは 禁句だって
教えたばっかりだろ！
(チョウジ)何か言った？
いや なんでもねえってばよ！
(いの)あっ サイ君！
これ 焼けたみたいよ！
Okay, time for some training.
What is it?
はい。
それ ボクの肉！
Well, it's been a long time
sinc
ちょっと いの！ さっきから
なに色目使ってんのよ！
気持悪い！
気持悪いってなによ！
あっ もしかして アンタ！
サイ君を独り占めするつもり!?
この デコデコ！
誰が デコデコだ！ この いのブタ！
おあいにくさま 私は サイなんか…。
もてない女が嫉妬!?
はあ？
まあ まあ サクラちゃん！
落ち着いてって…。
バカナルトは 黙ってて！
えっ!? バカ？
いのもやめなって！
うるさい デブ！
(ナルトたち)あっ!?
ボクは デブじゃない！
ポッチャリ系だ！
肉弾戦車！ ゴロゴロ ドッカーン！
あだ名って 難しいな…。